CHRISTOPHE FOYER

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com
United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • United Kingdom: (+44) 7444 175493
US and French citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

SUMMARY:

Mechanical Design Engineer with experience in projects in involving mechatronics and software development. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

- CAD, FEA and CFD
- Prototyping and Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)
- Engineering Hand Calculations
- Embedded Systems and Software Development

EXPERIENCE:

Temporary Works Design (TWD)

Design Engineer

London, United Kingdom Nov 2018 – Present

TWD is an engineering company specialized in creating custom-designed tools and structures to perform transport and installation projects.

- Design of bespoke equipment and structures for civil engineering contractors using Autodesk Inventor
- Verification of structural parameters using engineering hand calculations and finite element analysis

Tata Steel Europe

Mechanical Engineering Intern

Ijmuiden, Netherlands Apr 2018 – July 2018

Tata Steel is Europe's second largest steel producer, with steelmaking in the UK and Netherlands, and manufacturing plants across Europe.

- Successfully built a large-scale thermal simulation in Python reducing temperature estimation error by 82.4%
- Proof-of-concept enabling potential savings of around one million euros per year if implemented into production
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team Founder

Washington University in St. Louis Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

WUDBF is an aerospace-oriented engineering team that attends yearly competitions that are sponsored by the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA).

- Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

EDUCATION:

Washington University in Saint Louis

Saint Louis, USA

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

Aug 2014 - Dec 2017

Study Abroad: - RWTH Aachen, Germany (Summer 2017) - Energy & Mechatronics

- SIT Iceland (Summer 2015) - Energy Engineering and Economics

Lycée Sainte Marie

Caen, France Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

French Baccalauréat with honours - Science track

SKILLS:

CAD / FEA / CFD SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, XFLR5, RFEM

Programming Python, MATLAB, Simulink, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite wet layup (FG/CF), 3D-Printing, GD&T

Software / OS *Microsoft Office Suite, LaTeX, Windows, Linux*

Languages Native English and French (Bilingual) • Basic German and Icelandic

^{*}References available upon request

ACADEMIC PROJECTS:

Senior Design Project – Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS:

resume.cfoyer.com/#projects

FDM Tricopter Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing and electrical systems integration.

• Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Inventor and Netfabb

Motor Test Stand Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly.

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new Windows installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

Electric Longboard Oct 2016 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard.

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminum and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations

IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media centre system for personal use.

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (with added support for Windows and OSX)
- Control over house appliances and interfacing with Open Source Media Center (OSMC)

Robotics Test Platform Dec 2013 – Jan 2015

Coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing.

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over IP
- Experiments in visual odometry using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

Volunteering and Other Work Experience:

American Society of Mechanical Engineers

Washington University in St. Louis

Sep 2016 – May 2017

Event Planner

- Researched and presented to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus for \$45,000; secured a date for his visit
- Advised ASME members with ongoing projects on manufacturing and component selection.

Domaine du Vivier Seasonal farm hand Le Mesnil Mauger, France

Jun 2015 - Aug 2017

- Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work
- Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer

ICC
Volunteer

Ishinomaki, Japan
May 2014

• Construction of wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.